



With over 20 years industry experience, I specialize in Full-stack development of modern Node/React Javascript frameworks. I can work in front-end and back-end development and therefore lead a project from design, through to launch. I excel at finding software solutions to business problems. A full stack developer with extensive abilities in web application development, data modelling, database design and integration.

Excellent analytical skills and commercial awareness combined with the knowledge to handle the entire software development life cycle. Skilled in translating business requirements into technical solutions. Committed to quality, usability, security and scalability. I have designed software solutions driving continuous improvement to processes, systems, work ow and responsiveness. Great knowledge and working experience of software project methodologies.

Skills

React / Redux / Storybook	Serverless
Node	AWS / Lambda
Typescript	REST / API
TDD	GraphQL
Storybook	Nevt IS

Experience

Studio Rotate

Technical Lead September 2020 to February 2021

Node AWS Serverless Lambda/Step Functions Typescript Nuxt/Vue OAuth/JWT CI/CD

Solve complex performance problems and architectural challenges - Integration of data storage solutions.

- Build efficient, testable, and reusable modules and classes.
- Contribute to planning/concept/design of information architecture.
- Nuxt/Vue JS. Serverless/AWS
- Typescriptt

Promote best practices in all areas of software development.

- Build Node/ Serverless API, add libraries and develop functionality.
- Ensure components are built to detailed specifications.
- Configure payment services, webhooks and payment gateways. Build database schemas.
- OAuth/JWT token integration.

SportStack Contract Senior Frontend Developer

June 2020 to August 2020

Node GraphQL AWS Serverless Lambda Typescript React Jenkins

Develop and enhance the main front end platform - website.

- Writing reusable, testable, and efficient code. Well-practiced Test driven development.
- Design and implementation of low-latency, high-availability, and performant applications.
- Implementation of security and data protection.
- Integration of data storage solutions.

KarmaRama (Sainsburys) Contract Javascript Software Developer

March 2020 to June 2020

Node GraphQL AWS Serverless Lambda Typescript React

Refactor existing code source based on best-practices & standards. Develop middleware using GraphQL/nextJS for Google DV360 Advertising platform.

- Writing reusable, testable, and efficient code. Well-practiced Test driven development.
- Design and implementation of low-latency, high-availability, and performant applications.
- Implementation of security and data protection.
- Integration of data storage solutions.

KFC Western Europe Javascript Software Developer February 2019 to November 2019

Node React AWS Serverless Lambda Postgres Redis Typescript

Develop and design integrations between our digital ordering systems, point of sale system, payment solutions and related tools to support those systems. Develop internal applications to allow for digital orders placed through 3rd party integrations.

- Ensure data integrity between systems through integration layers.
- Migrated legacy codebase (Heroku) into new AWS Technical Architecture that supported a new digital transformation project whilst maintaining high availability for existing services with a broad scope that included frontend, backend, POS systems and Salesforce.
- Design and develop new user-facing and backend features.
- Develop specications and designs for complex applications whilst modifying/maintaining complex existing applications. • Perform code analysis, requirements analysis, identication of code metrics, system risk analysis and software reliability analysis.
- Performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, testing.
- Design and develop backend services and structure.

Pregin

Contract Javascript Software Developer November 2018 to February 2019

Node React Redux Typescript ElasticSearch

Develop and enhance the main front end platform - website. Design and develop new user-facing features.

- Develop specications and designs for complex applications or modifying/maintaining complex existing applications. Perform code analysis, requirements analysis, identication of code metrics, system risk analysis and software reliability analysis.
- Performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, testing.

MelodyVR

Contract Javascript Software Developer November 2018 to February 2019

Node React Redux AWS Serverless Lambda Typescript Linux

Develop/Design/Build a fullstack integration for a Content Management System using Node/React in AWS/Serverless. Integration of data storage solutions.

 Build efficient, testable, and reusable modules and classes. Conduct testing and deploy into production. Contribute to planning/concept/design of information architecture.

Determine business requirements and translate into component architecture within a limited timescale.

- Design and Develop React JS front-end application CMS. Provide technical support to the team during the devlopment of the application solution.
- Determine front-end application architecture. Initial integration into a AWS Cognito SDK using React/Redux Sagas pushing to CircleCI/AWS pipeline. Design/Develop CMS for company use. Semantic UI interface with React, immutable, redux sagas, jest/enzyme unit testing.

Big Clever Learning Contract Javascript Software Developer

April 2017 to November 2017

Node React Redux AWS Koa MicroServices Typescript OpenAPI Spec

Develop a series of microservice application architecture counselling applications. Solve complex performance problems and architectural challenges.

- Integration of data storage solutions. Build efficient, testable, and reusable modules and classes.
- Conduct testing and deploy into production. Updating, repairing, modifying and developing legacy code and generic applications. Contribute to planning/concept/design of information architecture.
- Contribute and add to Node microservices API, add libraries and develop functionality. Run environments through Docker containers and local services.
- Develop components for React applications for counselling services. • Build components to detailed specications. Congure payment services, webhooks to Stripe. Build database schemas.
- Jest/Mocha mock/dontMock unit testing. Redux/Redux Saga middleware.

Craft PHP JQuery Ajax

Futurebrand Contract PHP / Javascript Software

Developer October 2016 to March 2017

Develop and integrate OAuth services for global clients and further develop functionality for administration components. Build efficient, testable, and reusable modules and classes. Solve complex performance problems and architectural challenges, SAML & OAuth integration.

- Integration of data storage solutions. Conduct testing and deploy into production.
- Updating, repairing, modifying and developing legacy code and generic applications. Contribute to concept/pitching digital experiences for brands & agencies.
- Build Craft CMS PHP plugins to extend functionality of administration system for asset management services for global clients.

Purple Bridge Publishing Group Senior Developer / Team Lead January 2015 to September 2016

Laravel PHP JQuery Ajax DevOps MySQL Linux

Develop and lead dev team. Typical LAMP stack. Server congurations and pipeline setup, Docker containers. TDD Unit testing with PHPUnit. Design, develop, test, support and deploy custom web applications. Design and develop testing and maintenance procedures and activities. Assist and support junior team members on multiple projects. Implement best practices, standards and procedures. Develop and document design, source base and architecture. Maintain and manage existing code bases. Design, develop and implement solutions to user's needs and requirements.

- Write, review and improvise code.
- Coordinate with directors and business analysts to determine functionalities. Design and develop technical solutions to complex business problems.
- Design and develop data analysis solutions.
- Design and develop logical and physical data models that meet application requirements. Design, build and deploy web services including API, databases, websites and office management software.

Senior Software Developer

Business Support Analyst

March 2001 to February 2006

MediaCode

Orange

May 2006 to October 2014

PHP JQuery Ajax DevOps MySQL HTML Linux

Design, develop, and maintain custom applications that integrate with business applications. Interact with customers to develop business requirements.

- Define and document architecture and functional and design requirements.
- Conform to coding conventions and change control and product release policies. Participate in the continuous process improvement of solutions.
- Design and develop database management systems, image processing, collaborative tools, data manipulation, techniques, data visualization techniques, and directory services.

Laravel PHP JQuery Ajax DevOps MySQL

I worked in a business operations role for the global franchising team who operated internationally. I provided technical development and guidance for integration and migration of company branding for digital services.

 Work with other Analysts and users to understand business reporting requirements. Develop and implement report objects supporting end-user business requirements.

Education —

Marc Lally - marc.lally@gmail.com © Copyright 2020

 Assist in the creation of development standards and processes. Monitor jobs and troubleshoot the environment.

Work with Engineers to support them through integration into existing application layers. Design and develop automated applications and reporting solutions.

HSBC Software Engineer

1997 to 2001

PHP JQuery Ajax DevOps MySQL

I developed and provided technical support for online banking applications

With its strong focus on solving real-world problems through problem-based learning, this BSc delivers world-class, industry-relevant

BSc Computer Science

University College London

1990 - 1993

AWS Accreditation

teaching. The programme provides the essential material employers expect from a top-quality computer science graduate, and prepares you for employment in a wide variety of industries.

AWS Certified Developer - Associate December 2019 February 2020

AWS Accreditation

AWS Certified Solutions Architect -

major services in AWS.

Develop, deploy and debug cloud-based applications using AWS. Practical, hands-on skills for successfully developing with all the

Associate December 2019 February 2020

Thorough understanding how to make decisions between products and services on AWS, and how to begin architecting your own solutions on AWS.